onlinesurveybureau.com 2017-12-13

# Privacy Policy

#### Privacy Policy

** **  
Internet Research Bureau Private Limited (commonly known "IRB") is an Indian company registered with Ministry of Corporate Affairs, India, adheres the rules and regulations of Indian Government Companies Act. IRB owns and operates the website www.onlinesurveybureau.com. IRB is firmly committed to protect your privacy and avoid the dissemination of your personal information. You can directly contact us in case of any concerns related to our privacy practices at [privacy@irbureau.com](mailto:privacy@irbureau.com)

* * *

**Our Commitment**  
IRB is an online market research data collection company dedicated to provide high quality data to market research firms and other data collection companies. To protect your privacy and confidentiality is IRB's top priority. The data that IRB collects is only for market research purpose and IRB always reviews or publishes it as an aggregate information (about group). Individual information is never disclosed without your prior consent as it is irrelevant to the research conducted by IRB or IRB's clients. Registering as a member of Online Survey Bureau doesn't constitute the consent. Also this information is not disclosed to any other individual directly from IRB.   
**Personal Identifiable Information**  
At the time of registration site asks you to provide your basic personal information and once you are registered, it further asks you to update more personal and consumer information which helps us to find suitable surveys for you.  

* * *

**The site asks the below information:**  
**_E-Mail Address:_**  
So that we can contact you for the surveys, reward information, newsletters, company updates and notifications.  
**_Date of Birth:_**  
So that we can update your age automatically and invite you to participate in a suitable survey.  
**_Gender, Education Level, Household Income, Employment Status, Ethnic Background, Race, Zip Code/Postcode/Pin Code:_**  
So that we can invite you to participate in a suitable survey.  
**_Physical Address :_**   
So that we can contact you to process the payment of reward earned by you.  
**_Other Personal and Consumer Information:_**  
So that we can invite you to participate in a research survey with the qualifying criteria that best matches to your profile information. If you are not a member of Online Survey Bureau and we collect the personal identification information (e.g. e-mail ID, Date of Birth, Gender, Household Income, Education Level, Employment status, State/Province Zip Code/Postcode/Pin Code and IP Address), the only reason is to route you to the right surveys matching to the information. We ask for your email ID so that we can inform you when you qualify a survey and/or win the sweepstakes. If you have opted for the follow-up surveys, we might contact you if we need additional feedback for the particular survey. Apart from this there is no other reason to collect your personal information.   

* * *

**Use of Personal Information**  
The personal identifiable information collected by IRB is only used for the market research studies and not for any other purposes. We don't sell or share personal identifiable information of its panel members or the individuals who are not registered with us to any individual or its clients without your prior consent. If personal indefinable information is required in any of the research surveys, there will be a DND Agreement (Do Not Disclose Agreement) signed between IRB and the client to avoid the further usage and dissemination of the data. Also we ask you for your consent to participate in such surveys before sending you to the client's end. Participating in such surveys is completely your discretion.   
**Children's Privacy Policy**  
Children under age of 15 years are not eligible to join IRB panel. If we need responses from the children under age of 15 years, we seek their parents/guardians approval.  
**Data Validation Policy**  
We time to time conduct the data validation of our panel members and non-panel members with the help of third party(s) involvement, to ensure the quality of survey data, honesty and integrity of responses and uniqueness of members. We reserve the rights to terminate the membership of any panelist(s) and restrict the user(s) to participate in future surveys from Online Survey Bureau, if any discrepancy is found in the process of data validation. IRB signs the DND Agreement with third party before sharing the personal information of users for the purpose of data validation.  
**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**  
We use cookies on this site. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personal information you submit while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies to recognize the visitors, panelists, survey takers and new members coming to our website to join the survey community. Cookies also help us to identify the frequency of visitors and the number of unique users coming to our site that helps us to analyze the traffic on daily, weekly and monthly basis. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" directory. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.  
As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.   
We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.   
We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information. IP addresses are tied to personally identifiable information to identify your geo location in order to provide you suitable survey for you and prohibit the respondent from countries/places where we haven't started surveys yet.  
**Third Party Cookies**  
The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site, in order for you to use the shopping cart, etc.  
**Web beacons**  
Our Web pages contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns.  
**Widgets**  
Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button [and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site]. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.  
**Edit or Update Personal Information**  
Our members can update their personal information anytime they want by Logging in into their account. As soon as you update your personal information, you will be invited to the research surveys that match your newly updated information.  
**E-mail Opt-In Policy**  
As soon as you register with Online Survey Bureau, you authorize us to send you the account activation link and once you activate your account by clicking on the link sent in the account activation e-mail, you authorize us to send survey invitations, newsletters, reward information, notifications and company updates to the e-mail address you provided to us at the time of registration.  
**Opt-Out or Unsubscribe Policy**  
If you choose to terminate your membership or de-activate your account from Online Survey Bureau, you can do this by simply clicking on the "unsubscribe" button in My Accounts section on the website after logging in. The termination will take effect within four business days after the receipt of your notice. As soon as your account is de-activated, you will not be receiving any e-mail from us in future and your record will be deleted from our database. Once you unsubscribe from our site, the balance reward amount will get automatically lapsed.   
**Change or Modification of Privacy Policy**  
IRB reserves the right to change its privacy policy anytime. As soon as the privacy policy is changed or modified, it would be updated on the website under privacy policy section so kindly review it time to time. If we make any significant changes in the privacy policy, you will be notified via email.  
**Security Policy**  
IRB ensures that all the collected information from its members and users are secured on the server with best available technology. Personal information of the members and users is restricted and accessible to only few key members of IRB.  
**Agreement to Privacy Policy**  
By Signing up with Online Survey Bureau, directly participating in the surveys without signup and disclosing your personal information to us, you acknowledge your consent to, and in agreement with the privacy policy stated by IRB.  
**Contact Information**  
If you have any questions or concerns related to the privacy policy of IRB, kindly contact us at [privacy@irbureau.com](mailto:privacy@irbureau.com)

 _You can also mail us at the below physical address at :_  
**Internet Research Bureau Pvt. Ltd.**  
2A, 2nd Floor, Corner Market  
Malviya Nagar, New Delhi, 110017  
India
